Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory9 Mss.B.B61.inventory09
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents M
  - Matorin, N. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1932 Feb. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 8; teleg.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 22; teleg.
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 15; 2p.
  - Mattews, A. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1898 Nov. 26; 1p.
  - Matthews, Brander (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1909 Apr. 2
    - From Boas, 1909 Apr. 7
    - To Boas, 1909 Mar. 26
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 2
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 18
  - Matthews, J. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1916 Dec. 2
  - Matthews, Washington (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1889 Jan. 17
    - To Boas, 1889 Jan. 18
    - To Boas, 1889 Jan. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1889 Feb. 8
    - To Boas, 1897 Nov. 9; 2pp.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 24; 2pp.
  - Mattison, Norman D. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1936 June 3; 1p.
    - Matz, Leo A, 1940 Apr; 1p.
  - Matzdorff, C. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1914 Nov. 15
  - Mauco, G. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1937 Aug. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 May 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 June 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Aug. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Aug. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept. 22; 1p.
  - Maugard, A.B. (Box 62)
    Inuit designs
    - From Boas, 1926 Dec. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Dec. 7; 4pp.
  - Maurer, D.W. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 12; 1p.
  - Maurer, M.A. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1930 Aug. 1; 1p.
  - Maury, Carlotta J. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 7
    - From Boas, 1906 Apr. 6
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 5
    - To Boas, 1906 Apr. 9
  - Mausolff, Paul (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1920 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Dec. 7; 2pp.
  - Mauss, Marcel (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1927 Sept. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Apr. 19; 2pp.
    - To Boas, 1927 Jan. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Feb. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 15
      (see Bougle, C.)
  - Maxfield, J.P. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Apr. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 May 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 June 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Oct. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Nov. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Jan. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 May 24; 1p.
  - Maxwell, W.H. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1903 Oct. 7; 1p.
  - May (Box 62)
    (see Mandelbaum, May)
  - May, B. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 7; 2pp.
  - May, Jean Wise (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1933 June 7; 1p.
  - May, Stacy (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1934 Sept. 18; 1p.
  - Mayer, Bernhard (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 15; 2pp.
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 19
  - Mayer, Casper (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1912 Jan. 31
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 15
  - Mayer, Clara W. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1934 May 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 26; 1p.
      (Enc: Richtlinien fuer die Geschichtslehrbuecher)
    - To Boas, 1934 May 11; 2pp.
  - Mayer, Emil (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1929 Feb. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 26; 1p.
  - Mayer, George von L. (Box 62)
    - From Jesup, Morris K., 1905 Dec. 6
  - Mayer, J. (Box 62)
    - To Nixon, H.C., 1931 Sept. 15; 2pp.
  - Mayer, K. (Box 62)
    - From Beck, Charles, 1903 Jan. 1
  - Mayer, Mrs. Max W. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 23; 1p.
  - Mayer, Theresa (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1919 Mar. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 3; 2pp.
      Re Dr. A.A. Goldenweiser
    - (Enc. originally with Barnes, H.E., July 8, 1918), 1920 Sept.; 1p.
  - Mayerson, Augusta (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1935 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Dec. 2; 1p.
  - Mayhall, Mildred P. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 9; 1p.
  - Maynard, John A. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1920 May 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 14; 2pp.
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 16; 4pp.
    - John A. Maynard -- from M.E. Cronley, 1920 Aug. 16
  - Mayo-Smith, Richmond (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1898 Mar. 22
    - To Boas, 1898 Sept. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Feb. 11
  - Mbadiwe, Kingsley O. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1941 Dec. 1; 1p.
  - Mead, Charles H. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1908 Oct. 22
    - From Boas, 1908 Nov. 30
    - To Boas, 1908 Oct. 23
    - To Boas, 1908 Dec. 14
  - Mead, Mrs. Edward Sherwood (Box 62)
    (see Mead, Emily Fogg)
  - Mead, Emily Fogg (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 July 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Sept. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Aug. 19
    - To Boas, 1905 Oct. 19
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 8; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Apr. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 May 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 May 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Sept.5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Sept.; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 11; 1p.
  - Mead, Frances H. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr. 27
    - From Boas, 1909 Apr. 27
    - To Boas, 1894 May 26
    - To Boas, 1894 June 23
    - To Boas, 1894 June 29
    - To Boas, 1894 Oct. 22
    - To Boas, 1895 Nov. 16
    - To Boas, 1897 Aug. 23
    - To Boas, 1903 July 8
    - To Boas, 1903 Sept. 1
    - To Boas, 1906 May 3
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 28
    - To Boas, 1908 May 11
    - To Boas, 1908 Dec. 24
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 23
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 26
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 28
  - Mead, Margaret [Mrs. Bateson] (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1925 July 14; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1925 July 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Jan. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Jan. 25; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 15; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Sept. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Oct. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 July 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 July 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 July 24; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Aug. 29; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Sept. 17; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Oct. 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Nov. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Nov. 29; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Dec. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 5 and 6; (3p)
    - (see letter of Dec. 13, 1925, and that of Jan. 6, 1926 to Dr. Lillie), 1926 Jan. 6; 7p.
    - (Enc: with Mead, M. (to Lillie, F.D.) Jan. 6, 1926), 1926 Jan. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 16; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Feb. 15; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 7; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 14; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 24; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Apr. 7; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1926 May 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Sept. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Oct. 18; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Dec. 22; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 6; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 14; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 5; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Aug. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Aug. 23; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 July 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Sept. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 July 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - Margaret Mead -- to F.R. Lillie, 1926 Jan. 6; 1p.
  - Meade, Nelson P. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Nov. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 25; 1p.
  - Meader, C.L. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1938 June 7; 1p.
  - Meany, Edmond S. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1911 Feb. 24
    - From Boas, 1911 Mar. 13
    - To Boas, 1909 May 12
    - To Boas, 1911 Feb. 11; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Mar. 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Mar. 21; 2p.
  - Meany, Frank (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1911 Feb. 1
  - Mechling, William H. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1913 Feb. 14
    - From Boas, 1913 Nov. 12
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 4
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 19
    - To Boas, 1911 June 1
    - To Boas, 1912 Jan. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Feb. 6
    - To Boas, 1912 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Feb. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Feb. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 8
    - To Boas, 1912 June 9
    - To Boas, 1912 June 25
    - To Boas, 1912 Aug. 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Aug. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Apr. 12; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 17
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Mar. 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. 28
    - To Boas, 1915 Jan. 30; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1916 Oct. 13; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1916 Oct. 20; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - William H. Mechling -- to Tozzer, 1913 Nov. 10; 3p.
  - Medical Aid Committee Report (Box 62)
    - To Boas
    - (Enc: with Barsky, E.K., Apr. 24, 1940)
  - Medical Center Anti-War Committee (Box 62)
    (to College of Physicians and Surgeons. Faculty)
    - 1935 May 25, 3p.
  - Medizinische, Klinik Berlin, Germany (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1932 Apr. 26; 1p.
  - Meehan, Marjorie C. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 14; 1p.
    - Marjorie C. Meehan -- to Mrs. Rabi, 1938 Oct. 26; 1p.
  - Meek, J.W. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1908 Oct. 1
  - Meek, Lois H. (Box 62)
    - Lois H. Meek -- to R.F. Benedict, 1936 Sept. 24; 1p.
    - enc. Pourchet,M.N. to Columbian, Aug. 11
  - Meeks, Raymond (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 19
  - Meidner, Heinrich (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1897; 1p.
  - Meier, Johannes (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1922 Nov. 12; 1p.
  - Meier, Joseph Rev. Fr. M.S.C. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 May 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 2; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Apr. 2; 2p.
  - Meier, Norman C. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1930 Mar. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Mar. 20; 1p.
  - Meiklejohn, Alexander (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 5; 1p.
  - Meillet, A.? (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1930 May 10; 1p.
  - Meillet, Antoine (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1930 July 11; 1p.
  - Meinhof, K. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1925 Jan. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 June 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Apr. 26; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Aug. 7; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 July 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 29; 1p.
    - K. Meinhof -- from Thomas Yenser, 1926 Apr. 13
    - K. Meinhof -- from Komittee. Phonetisches Laboratorium d. Universität, 1927 July 23; 4p.
  - Meister, Leo (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1936 Aug. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 13; 1p.
  - Meitchoniuvbl, I.? (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1934 Sept.9; 2p.
  - Mekeel, H. Scudder (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1937 May 1; 1p.
  - Melior, M.A. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 25; 1p.
  - Meller, Eugenie Miscolczy (Box 62)
    - (see Catt, C.C., Feb. 10, 1937)
  - Meltzer, Mae (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1923 Oct. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 June 7; 1p.
  - Meltzer, S[amuel] J[ames] (?) (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1917 Oct. 18
    - From Boas, 1919 Feb. 26; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Mar. 1; 1p.
  - Memorandum, 1910 Dec. 29 (Box 62)
  - Mencia, Domingo (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1921 Dec. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Nov. 22; 1p.
    - also see Hernandez, E.A., 1921 Nov. 23; 1p.
  - Mencken, Henry Louis (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1926 Dec. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Aug. 8; 1p.
  - Mend, Charles W. (Box 62)
    - 1912 Dec. 14
  - Mendel, L[afayette] B[enedict] (?) (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1917 Oct. 18
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 26; 1p.
  - Mendel, Melvin (Box 62)
    - 1926 Apr. 30, 2p.
  - Mendelsohn, Charles J. (Box 62)
    - Charles J. Mendelsohn -- to the U. S. Dept. of Justice, 1917 Nov. 1
  - Mendelssohn Hall (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 20; 2p.
      (see Presby, Frank H.)
  - Mendenhall, W[alter] C[urran] (?) (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 May 4; 1p.
  - Mendte, Charles W. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 12
  - Menghin, Oswald (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1935 Feb. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 22; 3p.
  - Menorah Journal (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1938 June 24; 1p.
      (see Hurwitz, Henry)
  - Menschen und Menschenwerke (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 19; 1p.
  - Menz, Minna (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1930; 1p.
  - Menzel, Donald H. (Box 62)
    - Donald H. Menzel -- to F. R. Coudert, Jr.), 1941 Oct. 16; 2p.
  - Menzies, T. P. O. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 23; 1p.
  - Mercer, F. (/?) (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 12
  - Mercer, Samuel (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 17; 1p.
  - Mercer, William A. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1908 Jan. 27
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 29
  - Mercier, Ch. (Box 62)
    - Ch. Mercier -- to Joseph Schrijnen, 1929 June 27; 1p.
    - Ch. Mercier -- from Joseph Schrijnen, 1929 July 4
  - Meredith, A.B. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 22; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Oct. 27; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1915 Jan. 8; 2p.
  - Meriam, Lewis (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1912 Oct. 5
  - Meritt, Benjamin Dean (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1941 June 26; 1p.
  - Meritt, E.B. (Box 62)
    - E. B. Meritt -- to Clyde M. Blair, 1927 June 2; 1p.
  - Merkel, R.F. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct.; 2p.
    - (Enc: with Bertholet, Mar. 30, 1936)
  - Merriam, Charles E. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1924 Dec. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Jan. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Jan. 14; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 25; 1p.
    - Charles E. Merriam -- to E. R. Seligman, 1926 Mar. 3; 1p.
  - Merriam, C. Hart (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1908 Dec. 26
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 27
    - To Boas, 1889 July 13
    - To Boas, 1906 June 4
    - To Boas, 1908 Oct. 22
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 5
    - (see F. Boas to R.S. Woodworth, Sept. 2, 1931)
  - Merriam, John C. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 May 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 June 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Mar. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 15; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1919 May 19; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 28; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Dec. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Jan. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 July 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Nov. 24; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 May 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 June 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Sept. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Oct. 11; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Nov. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 May 23; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Oct. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Feb. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Apr. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 May 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 May 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Mar. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 May 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 May 7; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1935 May 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 May 29; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1935 June 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Sept. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 May 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 May 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 June 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Mar. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Mar. 29; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Apr. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Apr. 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Apr. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 May 20; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 July 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Aug. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Nov. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Feb. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 May 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 June 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Sept. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Nov. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Feb. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 May 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Nov. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Feb. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Mar. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Apr. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 May 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Nov. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 May 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 May 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 May 8; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1935 May 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1935 May 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 May 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 June 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Nov. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 5; 1p.
    - John C. Merriam -- to M.W. Beckwith
    - (Enc. originally with Beckwith, M.W. Nov. 27, 1924), 1924 Nov. 18; 1p.
    - John C. Merriam -- to A.L. Kroeber, 1909 Mar. 3
  - Merrill, E[lmer] D[rew] (?) (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1930 May 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 July 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 July 15; 2p.
  - Merrill, Frederick (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1906 Apr. 7
  - Merrill, Oscar Charles (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 11; 1p.
  - Merritt, Ernest (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1909 Sept. 22
  - Merwin, Raymond Edwin (Box 62)
    - (see Boas, F., May 14, 1906)
  - Merz, Charles (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1939 May 11; 1p.
      (Enc: clipping from N.Y. Times)
  - Mesirow, Mildred H. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 13; 1p.
  - Messer, Paula (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1925 Apr. 15; 6p.
  - Mestre, Aristides (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1935 Aug. 27; 1p.
  - Mestschaninoff (?) (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1936 May 11; 1p.
  - Metfessel, Milton F. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1928 June 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 June 7; 1p.
  - Métraux, Alfred (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Dec. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Sept. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Dec. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Aug. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas (open letter), 1936 Jan. 28
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - Alfred Métraux -- to R.F. Benedict, 1939 June 30; 2p.
    - Alfred Métraux -- to Alvin Johnson, 1940 Oct. 2; 1p.
  - Métraux, Eva (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1935 Sept. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Sept. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct. 5; 1p.
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Co. (Box 62)
    (see Christiernin, Charles L.)
    (see Dublin, Louis)
    (see Fellows, H. H.)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 62)
    (see Kent, Henry W.)
  - Metropolitan Storage Warehouse Co. (Box 62)
    - From Boas, 1907 Sept. 11
  - Metz, Herman A. (Box 62)
    - Herman A. Metz -- to Germanistic Society of America, 1920 Feb.; 2p.
  - Meus, M. (Box 62)
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 9; 3p.
  - Mexico (Box 62)
    - From Boas to National Museum, 1925 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Oct. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas to Minister of Public Education, 1925 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas to Secretary of Public Education: Dept. of Monuments, 1936 Jan. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas to Secretary of Public Instructions:Fine Arts, 1911 July 19
    - To Boas from Biblioteca de la direccion de estudios arquelogicos, 1917 Aug. 13; 2p.
    - To Boas from Secretary of Public Instruction:Fine Arts, 1913 Aug. 19
    - To Boas from Museo Nacional de Arqueologia
      (see Caso, Alfonso)
    - To Boas from Secretario de Pelaciones Exteriores, 1910 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas from Universidad Nacional, 1914 Sept. 12; 1p.
  - Meyer, A.B. (Box 63)
    - To Boas, 1901 Feb. 2; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1902 May 23; 2p.
  - Meyer, Adolf (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 28
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 28
    - From Boas, 1908 Oct. 1
    - From Boas, 1908 Dec. 11
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 7
    - To Boas, 1906 May 1
    - To Boas, 1908 Sept. 23
    - To Boas, 1908 Dec. 9
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb. 24; 1p.
  - Meyer, Alfred (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 July 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 July 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 July 9; 1p.
  - Meyer, Anna E. H. (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 May 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1902 Nov. 14
    - To Boas, 1919 Mar. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 7; 1p.
  - Meyer, Annie N. (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1936 July 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Aug. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933(?)Nov. (?); 2p.
    - To Boas, 1936 July
  - Meyer, A. O. (Box 63)
    - A. O. Meyer -- to Deutsche Akademie, 1934 Dec. 31
  - Meyer, A. R. (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1905 Sept. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Sept. 18; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Sept. 22; 1p.
  - Meyer, Eduard (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1915 Oct. 22; 12p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Dec. 23; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 19; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Mar. 5; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1910 Jan. 27; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1913 June 18; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1915 July; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Jan. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1924 July 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 May 26; 2p.
  - Meyer, Florence A. (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1918 July 12; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 11; 2p.
  - Meyer, F.W. (?) (Box 63)
    - To Boas, 1925 July 15; 1p.
  - Meyer, Hans (Box 63)
    - To Boas, 1936 Oct. 29; 1p.
  - Meyer, Helene (Box 63)
    - Helene Meyer -- from H. C. Kudlich, 1918 June 13; 1p.
  - Meyer, J. (?) (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1904 May 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 31
      (see Ridder, Herman)
  - Meyer, J.J. (?) (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1937 Oct. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 16; 1p.
  - Meyer, Julius P. (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1925 Feb. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Feb. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Oct. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 25
    - To Boas, 1923 Mar. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - (Enc: Letter of introduction for Drs. Weber and Habig), 1927 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - See Hamburg American Line, Meyer, J. P., 1929 Jan. 12
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 10; 1p.
  - Meyer, Louise (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1908 Oct. 16
    - From Boas, 1909 May 12
    - To Boas, 1910 Aug. 15
  - Meyer, Max F. (Box 63)
    - See Boas, F. Open letter on culture and democracy in Spain. Replies, 1938 Jan.
  - Meyer, Paul (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 6; 1p.
  - Meyer, Theodore (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 1; 1p.
  - Meyer, Willy (Box 63)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 29; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 July 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Nov. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Oct. 13; 1p.